<Chapter Label="cet">
<Heading>Cubic edge-transitive graphs</Heading>

In this Chapter we give functions for accessing the cubic edge-transitive 
graphs stored in this package, and related properties. Currently, this
package contains all connected cubic edge-transitive graphs on up to 10000
vertices. For information and references on these graphs, see 
<Cite Key="CD_2002"/> and <Cite Key="CMMP_2006"/> (note: these references do 
not cover the enumeration of graphs on more than 768 vertices, but the authors
are currently writing up the extended computations for publishing).
<P/>
Let <M>\Gamma</M> be a simple graph (undirected, loopless, without multiple 
edges). Then <M>\Gamma</M> is <E>cubic</E> (or <E>trivalent</E>, or 
<M>3</M><E>-valent</E>) if each vertex of the graph has exactly 3 neighbours.
<P/>
The graph <M>\Gamma</M> is <E>edge-transitive</E> if the automorphism group 
of <M>\Gamma</M> acts transitively on the edges of <M>\Gamma</M>.
<P/>
A regular edge-transitive graph can be either vertex-transitive or 
non-vertex-transitive. In the former case the graph is arc-transitive, and in 
the latter case it is said to be <E>semisymmetric</E>. Currently in the 
&GraphSym; package, if a user wants access to a cubic edge-transitive graph they
must also specify if the graph is arc-transitive or semisymmetric.


<Section Label="Accessing the cet graphs">
<Heading>Accessing the cubic edge&ndash;transitive graphs</Heading>

In this Section we introduce functions for the access to the cubic 
edge-transitive graphs stored in the &GraphSym; package.

<#Include Label="CubicATGraph">

<#Include Label="CubicSSGraph">

<#Include Label="AllCubicATGraphs">

<#Include Label="AllCubicSSGraphs">

<#Include Label="CubicATGraphIterator">

<#Include Label="CubicSSGraphIterator">

</Section>

<Section Label="cet library info">
<Heading>Properties of the cubic edge&ndash;transitive graphs and library</Heading>

In this Section we give the functions which give information about the cubic
edge-transitive graphs library, and the properties and attributes of the 
graphs it contains.

<Subsection Label="Precomputed data cet">
<Heading>Precomputed attributes of the cubic edge&ndash;transitive graphs</Heading>

Currently, there are no precomputed attributes available for the cubic 
edge-transitive graphs stored in this package. In the near future, we plan to
provide several attributes for each of the cubic edge-transitive graphs stored, 
including diameter, girth and bipartiteness. 
<!--
For a given cubic edge-transitive graph <M>\Gamma</M> stored in this package, 
there are several precomputed attributes stored in the &GraphSym; package. These 
include the following:

<List>
<Item>The diameter of <M>\Gamma</M> 
      (<Ref BookName="Digraphs" Attr="DigraphDiameter"/>).</Item>
<Item>The girth of the <M>\Gamma</M> 
      (<Ref BookName="Digraphs" Attr="DigraphUndirectedGirth"/>).</Item>
<Item>The bipartiteness of <M>\Gamma</M> 
      (<Ref BookName="Digraphs" Attr="IsBipartiteDigraph"/>).</Item>
<Item>The Cayleyness of <M>\Gamma</M>
      (<Ref Prop="IsCayleyGraph"/>).</Item>
<Item>The arc-transitiveness of <M>\Gamma</M>
      (<Ref Prop="IsArcTransitiveDigraph"/>).</Item>   
</List>
-->

</Subsection>

Now we introduce functions which are used to find information about
the library and each of the graphs it stores.

<#Include Label="NrCubicATGraphs">

<#Include Label="NrCubicSSGraphs">

<#Include Label="CubicATGraphId">

<#Include Label="CubicSSGraphId">

<#Include Label="SetCubicATGraphProps">

<#Include Label="SetCubicSSGraphProps">

</Section>

</Chapter>
